# **Shile Zhang**

# shirleyzhang@knights.ucf.edu

linkedin.com/in/shile-zhang-e-i-b7609917b

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

Two years of working experience from multiple funded projects, involving traffic safety under Connected Automated Vehicle (CAV) environment, data analytics, statistical analysis, and IoT device development.

Fluent in programming languages such as Python, and traffic software such as ArcGIS.

Dedicated and self-motivated professional, work cooperatively with others.

Strong verbal and written communication skills.

## **EDUCATIONS**

# **University of Central Florida**

Orlando, FL, U.S.

Ph.D. in Civil Engineering (Transportation)

Aug 2018-May 2021(expected)

Graduates Certificate, SAS Data Mining

Aug 2018-Sep 2020

Master of Science in Civil Engineering (Smart Cities)

Aug 2018-Apr 2020

Southeast University Nanjing, China

Bachelor of Science in Traffic Engineering

Aug 2012-Jun 2016

## SKILL AND SOFTWARE

Programming Python, MATLAB, C++, SQL

Traffic software AutoCAD, TransCAD, NADS MiniSim, ArcGIS

Statistical software R, SAS

Other software Microsoft Office, Latex

## **ORGANIZATIONS**

UCF Smart and Safe Transportation Lab

Member

Institute of Transportation Engineers (ITE) at UCF

Executive Board

Woman in Transportation (Central Florida Chapter)

Member

# **JOURNAL ARTICALS**

**Zhang, S.**, Abdel-Aty, M., Yuan, J., & Li, P. (2020). Prediction of Pedestrian Crossing Intentions at Intersections Based on Long Short-Term Memory Recurrent Neural Network. Transportation Research Record. https://doi.org/10.1177/0361198120912422.

Wu, Y., Abdel-Aty, M., Zheng, O., Cai, Q., **Zhang, S.**, (2020). Automated Safety Diagnosis Based on Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Video and Deep Learning Algorithm. Transportation Research Record. https://doi.org/10.1177/0361198120925808.

**Zhang, S.**, Abdel-Aty, M., Cai, Q., Li, P., Ugan, J., 2020. Prediction of pedestrian-vehicle conflicts at signalized intersections based on long short-term memory neural network. Accident Analysis & Prevention. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aap.2020.105799.

**Zhang, S.**, Abdel-Aty, M., Wu, Y., Zheng, O., 2020. Modeling pedestrians' near-accident events at signalized intersections using gated recurrent unit (GRU). Accident Analysis & Prevention 148, 105844.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

# Using Smartphone as On Board Unit (OBU) Emulator Implementation Study

Florida Department of Transportation

*Oct* 2018 – *Sep* 2019

Task: Using a smartphone application and machine learning to send warning to drivers.

# **Connecting the East Orlando Communities Project (Phase I, Smart Garage)**

Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) ATCMTD

Aug 2019 – Aug 2020

Task: Using Raspberry Pi to identify empty parking spots and backing vehicles in the garage.

# Improving Vulnerable Road Users' Safety Based on Computer-Vision Technologies (Phase I)

Florida Department of Transportation

Aug 2020 – Aug 2021

Task: Predicting pedestrians' red-light crossing behaviors and safety conditions using CCTV videos.

## **HONORS AND AWARDS**

ORC Doctoral Fellowship (stipend: \$25,000)

Aug 2018

University of Central Florida

**Solving for Safety Visualization Challenge (team award)** 

Nov 2019

U.S. Department of Transportation

**UCF Graduate Presentation Fellowship** 

Jan 2020

University of Central Florida

#### **CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES**

#### Coursera

Getting Started with AWS Machine Learning

Jun 2020

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/V9SA78DBNJ29

# Florida Board of Professional Engineers

Engineer [Intern]

Oct 2020

https://account.ncees.org/rn/2057425-1334109-c629ac6

# Coursera

Computer Vision Basics

Oct 2020

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9QUHWSP55J23